In this video, we're going to talk about
a deep research agent that can not only
do web search for you, but can also
control your browser and it has a number
of MCB tools that can create word
documents, PDF files and a lot more.
This is an open-source project called
deep research agent which is based on
this paper agent orchestra a
hierarchical multi- aent framework for
generalpurpose task solving. The focus
is on journal purpose tasks. Now this is
from a company called Skywork AI who are
also the kind sponsors of today's video
and it's a very interesting company.
They have been open sourcing some very
interesting projects. So for example
here is a 3D world that is created from
a single input image. The project itself
is completely open source. You can
download and play around with this. Or
they have this other matrix game uh 2.0
Nintendo again an open-source world
model where you can actually play the
game and it creates all the scenes in
real time. They're also creating a
platform called Skywork super agent
where you can create word document u
slides do analysis on your excel sheets
also has a web page developer you can
create par podcast and a lot more on
that later in the video. Okay, so coming
back to the deep uh research agent
framework, they're doing some very neat
and interesting things especially when
it comes to the MCP manager agent part.
So they're trying to build for general
purpose task solving which means you
cannot just rely on pre-existing tools.
You need to have a mechanism in which
you create new tools based on your need
and that's exactly what they are doing.
So, your agent needs to have the ability
to look at the user intent, then look at
the list of available tools. If the task
can't be solved by pre-existing tools,
then it should be able to synthesize
tools for that specific task. Then
there's a multi-stage evaluation
protocol that validates that the tool
actually does what it's supposed to do
and then registers that new tool in the
MCP server for any subsequent tasks
which is an extremely neat idea and I
think it's going to become uh more
prevalent as uh these models and agents
have more agency. So you're going to be
able to build uh tools on demand and
after some time you can just discard
that tool if the agent is uh not using
it anymore. Okay. So here's the main
architecture of this system. At the core
is the planning agent and then there are
a number of different agents. The first
one is deep analyzer agent. So this
performs in-depth analysis of input
information. uh it extracts key insights
and potential requirements and also
supports analysis of various different
data types including text and structured
data. Each of these dedicated agents
also have a Python uh code interpreter.
So it can run and execute codes and then
analyze the results. Then we have a deep
researcher. So this conducts thorough
research on uh specified topics or
questions. It retrieves and synthesize
high quality information and is capable
of generating research reports and
knowledge summaries automatically. So
think of this as a deep research agent
that uh chat GPT uh Gemini or clot
provides. Then they also have this
dedicated browser use agent. So this can
automatically browse u the internet. Uh
it supports web search information
extraction and data collection tasks and
this can be used in conjunction with the
deep researcher uh if it needs any
up-to-date information from the
internet. And last but not the least, we
have the MCP uh manager agent uh that
basically manages the MCP tools and
services. And the good thing is that it
dynamically um performs uh or enables
tool discovery, registration and
execution through the standard MCP
protocol.
U through this you can also have both
local and remote MCP tool integration uh
which is pretty neat. Now in terms of
the overall uh functionality
uh you have different tools which are
going to um perform different actions
and based on the output of those tools
the system is able to update its plan.
So here's how it usually works. You have
uh the user objective that comes in um
it performs or tries to interpret the
task using um let's say the deep
analyzer agent. it decomposed into
subtasks then picks specialized uh sub
aents for those tasks. Uh those sub
aents are going to have different tools
and um if a new tool is needed that can
be created on the fly. Also when when an
operation is performed uh it can collect
those errors and updates its uh both
plan and objectives.
So this would be an example of a multi-
aent system that can not only do simple
web search and synthesize reports but
also can take actions using these tools
and agents that are available.
Now the code is available on GitHub. Uh
so you can run this in your local
environment. But there is one more
interesting thing that I want to
highlight and that is if you look at um
the different models that different
agents use. It's not just one model or
one provider. So here it relies on
Google uh I think BU as well. Uh it also
uses openw weight models like Quinn
along with uh open AI models right. So
this is extremely flexible and it also
shows you that different models have
different capabilities and strengths. So
if you're building a multi- aent system,
don't limit yourself to a single
provider.
Uh and they also have a pretty neat
looking uh and pretty functional website
which basically explains these um uh
different agents how they work
especially with a focus on the MCP uh
manager agent tool. Uh this seems to be
developed using the super agent which
we're going to look at later in the
video. But overall um this agent
orchestrator or orchestra is the best
performing agent on the GA IA benchmark
and also gets u close to
state-of-the-art results on the human um
humanity last exam benchmark.
And again the best part is that all of
this is uh built on top of their
open-source projects uh and tools which
is pretty awesome.
Also, I just noticed that uh one of the
contributors to this project is Google's
uh uh Jews, which is pretty neat to see.
So, we're seeing actually more and more
code being um contributed the by these
coding agents or using these coding
agents.
Okay. So, here are again the results
based on the uh GA benchmark. Now,
interestingly enough, um if you look at
these results, uh adding MCP u dynamic
tool creation does help uh this specific
agent framework.
Apart from this, they have also some
very interesting other open source
project. For example, this R1 V3 which
is an open-source multimodel reasoning
model that is trained with um
reinforcement fine-tuning
or there's Skye's V2 infinite length uh
film generative model.
They also have their own image
generation understanding and editing
model.
Now all of this and more is packaged
together in their new Skywork
uh super agents. So think of this as a
competitor to something like Manace or
Genpark. It can do document creation
based on um search.
So it's able to collect uh user input
and then uh perform web search and
create high quality documents for you.
During the process, it uses different
MCP tools. Uh for example, it's doing
web search right now. It's browsing
those pages, right? So, it's able to use
these different tools to create very
appealing documents.
It's able to use different tools. So for
example uh here they were um doing or
calling uh web search and then uh using
the browse tool to read the contents and
on top of that uh it was doing uh
information aggregation from those uh
web pages.
So here is the uh final results based on
that uh it not only performed market uh
search analysis but also created these
different plots which are representative
of the data that it has seen.
So this is definitely a new trend that
we are seeing uh with these agents
because they are being used for document
and report generation.
It can also do data analysis. So, uh it
can look for information then uh create
um sheets for you. Uh or you can provide
your own Excel sheets and then updated
using uh the agent. So it's able to do
most of the things that uh something
like uh file creation in cloud or
analysis uh that is going to be
performed by
another use case is uh its ability to
work with CSV files or create sheets for
you. So for example uh you can ask it to
uh do web search and collect data in the
form of Excel sheets or you can provide
your own data. So in this example uh it
collected some data from the internet
and then you can see that uh the agent
is able to create uh plots uh also does
[clears throat] some uh sales analysis
year-over-year comparison uh and I can
also look at quarterly trends right so
it's a very powerful agentic system
because it not only has access to just a
deep researcher tool but also has these
other tools like Python code interpreter
where it can actually perform analysis
for you. It also has a tool uh for
building websites. So think about this
as uh computator to loable right. So
based on your requirement, it does uh
web search collects data from different
websites and then it can render those in
the form of a pretty decent looking web
pages.
So in this case, here's the final output
uh that it um created. Uh really
functional. It has all the features that
um we wanted and also um it collected
all of this data using this deep
research tool.
One interesting demo that they have is
uh the models or agents ability to um
look at YouTube videos and then create
uh tutorials based on that.
So for example, here's a a lecture
lecture from one of the MIT courses
and here uh the agent is creating
um a really interesting mind map of all
the topics that are being discussed. Now
this uh type of functionality is
available natively within Gemini uh 2.5
Pro or Gemini Flush. But here you have a
single agent that can do a lot of
different things. And again, this is
built on top of the deep agent
architecture that we looked at it
before.
They also just opened up their uh API.
So, you can do all of these things
through their API, which is going to be
pretty neat.
They're also opening up their API. So,
you'll be able to do some of these
things through the API. So, for example,
you can ask the agent to create
documents for you uh through the API. So
if you want to build uh something on top
of this, this is I think a really good
option.
You do get some free credits um to test
this out. Uh but then they have
different packages based on your needs.
So do check them out and I personally
really like their approach of building
on top of their open-source work and
sharing their research as well as models
with the community. So do let me know
what you think. Anyways, I hope you
found this video useful. Thanks for
watching and as always, see you in the
next one.